Karen Ma

karenma333@gmail.com | karenma.me | linkedin.com/in/karenma333

Summary

Skills Product Strategy | Requirements Gathering | User Research | Technical Design |

Qualitative Ethnography | User Testing | Web Analytics | User Experience Design

Software | Axure | Adobe XD | Figma | Google Analytics | Looker | Sketch

Experience

NextCapital - Lead Designer

Sept 2019 - Present

Previously: Full Stack Product Designer

Oct 2018 - Sept 2019

- Led the product design and development of new features to increase the size of existing user base by 68% and increase the new user aggregation rate by 5x
- Drove the redesign of the primary product into a new design system by aligning team members on scope, conducting design reviews and critiques, engaging with key stakeholders in the design process
- Defined new guidelines, from content strategy to interaction patterns to create a design system on top of the existing visual design library
- Evangelized the usage of user research in the product development process, using tools such as SurveyMonkey, UsabilityHub, in-person moderated user testing sessions
- Building out a web analytics foundation for design and product to measure success of features and review usability issues, using data analytics software, Looker, Segment and built-in Google Analytics.
- Shaped design culture through design and people mentorship, hosting quarterly educational presentations to provide continuing education opportunities

Education

University of California, San Diego BS Cognitive Science (Human Computer Interaction) — 2018 Minor: Computer Science

Activities

Industry Advisor - America Needs You

June 2020 - Sept 2020

In partnership with ANY, I acted as a mentor for a first-generation college student by creating a 3 month software engineering internship challenge and guided them through the completion of the project.

Design4SD — Research Assistant

Jan 2017 - Jun 2017

I worked in the UCSD Design Lab under Steven Dow and Narges Mayhar working on investigating better ways to encourage and promote participatory design when it comes to civic design challenges.